Guide to the Norman E. Thomas Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
Norman E. Thomas Papers
1953-2011
RG 112
Yale University Divinity School Library
38
(87 boxes)
Correspondence, writings, course-related material, and subject files document the work of Norman E. Thomas. Norman E. Thomas is a prominent missiologist, theological educator, and historian of world Christianity. A Yale graduate, he served as a missionary in Africa, missions administrator for the United Methodist Church, Director of the Mission and Evangelism Program and Boston University School of Theology, and Professor of World Christianity at United Theological Seminary in Dayton, Ohio prior to his retirement.
Thomas, Norman E.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Norman E. Thomas
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Biographical / Historical
1932 Mar 29 Born in Manchester, NH
1953 Received B.A. from Yale College
1956 Received M.Div. from Yale Divinity School
1956-1959 Pastor of Errol Heights United Methodist Church, Portland, OR
1961-1967 National Director of Christian Education and Youth Work, The United Methodist Church, Rhodesia [Zimbabwe]. Administered a teacher training and curriculum development program for 1,400 teachers of Bible in elementary and secondary schools, and for volunteer teachers and youth leaders in 300 congregations.
1967-1970 Urban Secretary, Christian Council of Rhodesia. Developed new program of joint church action by Protestant and Catholics in Rhodesia's towns and cities.
1968 Received Ph.D. in Social Ethics and Sociology of Religion, with concentration in African studies, from Boston University
1968-1972 Senior Lecturer and Dean of Students, United Theological College, Salisbury, Rhodesia.
1973 Visiting Lecturer in Religion and Society, Pacific School of Religion and the Graduate Theological Union, Berkeley, CA
1973-1976 Dean of Studies and Associate Director, Mindolo Ecumenical Foundation, Kitwe, Zambia
1976-1978 Staff Associate, the Africa Task Force, Board of Global Ministries, United Methodist Church, New York
1977-1978 Visiting Lecturer in Missions, Yale Divinity School
1978 Visiting Professor of Humanities and International Studies, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, VA
1978-1983 Director, Mission and Evangelism Program, and Lecturer, Boston University School of Theology
1983-2001 Vera B. Blinn Professor of World Christianity, United Theological Seminary, Dayton, OH
Scope and Contents
I. Correspondence
II. Published Writings
III. Unpublished Writings and Lectures
IV. Course-Related Material
V. Documentation Files by Subject
VI. Documentation Files by Institution
VII. Biographical Documentation
The papers have been retained in the scheme of organization in which they were received. Series I, Correspondence, is divided into chronological segments. Series II, Published Writings of Norman E. Thomas, is divided into three sub-series:Book-length works, Articles and Chapters in Symposia, and Book Reviews. Series III, Unpublished Writings and Lectures is divided into two sub-series: Public lectures, and Book manuscripts. Series IV contains materials for courses taught by Thomas throughout his career, arranged alphabetically by course topic. Series V consists of the extensive subject files compiled by Thomas. The letter codes preceding topics are Thomas's classification system, somewhat based on the Library of Congress system.. Series VI provides documentation related to various institutions with which Thomas was involved during the course of his career. Series VII contains biographical information about Thomas.
Arrangement
I. Correspondence
II. Published Writings
III. Unpublished Writings and Lectures
IV. Course-Related Material
V. Documentation Files by Subject
VI. Documentation Files by Institution
VII. Biographical Documentation
Missions and Christian union; Missions; Educators; Thomas, Norman E.
- Correspondence, Series I
  - A. 1953-1961
    - Correspondence, 1953-1961 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - B. 1962-1972
    - Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - C. 1973-1976
    - Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - D. 1976-1983
    - Correspondence: General, 1976-1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: Research, 1976-1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - E. 1983-2000
    - Correspondence: General, 1983-2000 (Box 1, Folder 6-9)
    - Correspondence: ASM Bibliography Project, 1983-2000 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence: Missiology-Book Editor: with reviewers, 1983-2000 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence: Missiology- with editors, 1983-2000 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence: Missiology-Book Editor: with publishers, 1983-2000 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence: Speaking, 1983-2000 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence: Writing: Proposals, 1983-2000 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Published Writings of Norman E. Thomas, Series II
  - Book-length works
    - Ngatiimbe Pamwe: Choruses for Youth. Umtali, Rhodesia: The Board of Communication of hte Methodist Church, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Ndwiyo dze Vana: Children's Song Book. Umtali, Rhodesia: The Board of Communication of the Methodist Church, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Christianity, Politics and the Manyika: A Study of the Influence of Religious Attitudes and Loyalities on Political Values and Activities of Africans in Rhodesia. Ann Arbor, MI: University Microfilms, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - The Church's Mission in Rhodesia's Towns. Salisbury, Rhodesia: Christian Council of Rhodesia. Editor., 1969 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - The Church and Rapid Urban Growth in Southern Africa. Salisbury, Rhodesia: The Southern Africa Contact Group on Urban Mission of the All-Africa Conference of Churches. Editor., 1970 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Self-Reliance in Zambia: The Zambia Report for the Non-governmental Organization for Habitat, the United Nation's Forum on Human Settlements. Kitwe, Zambia: Mindolo Ecumentical Foundation. Edited by B.W. Shonga and N.E. Thomas, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Marriage Patterns in Kitwe, Zambia. Kitwe, Zambia: Mindolo Ecumentical Foundation., 1977 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Rise Up and Walk: An Autobiography by Abel T. Muzorewa. Nashville, TN: Abingdon; London: Evans Bros. Editor., 1978 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Long-range Planning Report, Fairview United Methodist Church, Dayton, OH. Dayton, OH: Fairview United Methodist Church. Edited by Scott Sheely and Norman E. Thomas., 1985 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Evangelism: A Basic Bibliography. Chicago, IL: American Theological Library Association [ATLA]., 1989 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Missions: A Basic Bibliography. Chicago, IL: American Theological Library Association [ATLA]., 1989 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Readings in World Mission. London, England: SPCK.Editor, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Classic Texts in Mission and World Christianity. Maryknoll, NY: Orbis Books, 1995. Editor. [in "150 Outstanding Books for Mission Studies: 1990-1999", International Bulletin of Missionary Research 24, no.2 (April 2000).] (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Classic Texts: Correspondence: Planning, 1992-1995 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Classic Texts: Book Reviews, 1996-1999 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Classic Texts: Source materials: Proposal (Box 79, Folder 702)
    - Classic Texts: Source materials: Eastern Church (Box 79, Folder 703)
    - Classic Texts: Source materials: Protestant Reformation (Box 79, Folder 704)
    - Classic Texts: Source materials: Enlightenment (Box 79, Folder 705)
    - Classic Texts: Source materials: Church with Others (Box 79, Folder 706)
    - Classic Texts: Source materials: Missio Dei (Box 79, Folder 707)
    - Classic Texts: Source materials: Mediating Salvation (Box 79, Folder 708)
    - Classic Texts: Source materials: Quest for Justice (Box 79, Folder 709)
    - Classic Texts: Source materials: Evangelism (Box 80, Folder 710)
    - Classic Texts: Source materials: Contextualization (Box 80, Folder 711)
    - Classic Texts: Source materials: Liberation (Box 80, Folder 712)
    - Classic Texts: Source materials: Inculturation (Box 80, Folder 713)
    - Classic Texts: Source materials: Common Witness (Box 80, Folder 714)
    - Classic Texts: Source materials: People of God (Box 80, Folder 715)
    - Classic Texts: Source materials: Witness to Other Faiths (Box 80, Folder 716)
    - Classic Texts: Source materials: Theology (Box 80, Folder 717)
    - Classic Texts: Source materials: Action in Hope (Box 80, Folder 718)
    - Classic Texts: Source materials: Miscellaneous (Box 80, Folder 719)
    - Adventurous Living: Selected Writings of G. Ernest Thomas. Dayton, OH: U.T.S. Press. Editor, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Teks-Teks Klasik Tentang Misi dan Kekristenan Sedunia [Classic Texts in Mission and World Christianity]. Translated into Bahasa Indonesia by Stephen Suleeman. Jakarata, Indonesia: Gunung Mulia., 1998 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Missions and Unity: Lessons from History, 1792-2010 (Box 86, Folder 4)
    - Missions and Unity: Source materials: Introduction - Chapter 3 (Box 86, Folder 5)
    - Missions and Unity: Source materials: Chapters 4 - 6 (Box 86, Folder 6)
    - Missions and Unity: Source materials: Chapter 7 (Box 86, Folder 7)
    - Missions and Unity: Source materials: Chapter 8 (Box 86, Folder 8)
    - Missions and Unity: Source materials: Chapter 9 (Box 86, Folder 9)
    - Missions and Unity: Source materials: Chapter 10 (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Missions and Unity: Source materials: Chapter 11 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - Missions and Unity: Source materials: Chapter 12 (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - Missions and Unity: Source materials: Chapter 14 (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - Missions and Unity: Source materials: Chapter 15, Conclusion (Box 87, Folder 5)
  - Article-length writings
    - Articles and chapters in symposia, 1966-1991 (Box 3, Folder 4-23)
    - Articles and chapters in symposia, 1992-2001 (Box 4, Folder 1-10)
    - Articles and chapters in symposia, 2002-2005 (Box 85, Folder 8)
    - Articles and chapters in symposia, 2007-2011 (Box 86, Folder 1)
  - Book Reviews
    - Book reviews, 1980-2001 (Box 4, Folder 11-14)
    - Book reviews, 2002-2006 (Box 85, Folder 6)
    - Book reviews, 2007 (Box 86, Folder 2)
- Unpublished Writings and Lectures, Series III
  - Public Lectures (Chronologically by year)
    - Public lectures, 1969-1985 (Box 4, Folder 15-23)
    - Public lectures, 1986-1997 (Box 5, Folder 24-35)
    - Public lectures, 1998-2001 (Box 6, Folder 36-40)
    - Public lectures, 2004-2006 (Box 85, Folder 7)
    - Public lectures, 2008, 2010 (Box 86, Folder 3)
  - Unpublished Book Manuscripts
    - Mission 2000 (Box 6, Folder 41-45)
- Course-Related Material, Series IV
  - Syllabi, bibliographies and papers by course, school, and year
    - African Development (VPISU), 1978 (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - Biblical Witness and Christian Mission (UTS), 1993 (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Biblical Witness and Christian Mission (UTS): Addendum, 1993 (Box 82, Folder 6)
    - Calling-Caring Ministries (UTS), 1986,1987 (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Christian Approaches to Other Faiths (UTS), 1984,1986, 1989, 1991,1996 (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - Christian Approaches to Other Faiths: addendum (Box 83, Folder 5)
    - Christian Education (ETC, Rhodesia), 1972 (Box 6, Folder 50-52)
    - Christian Ethics (ETC, Rhodesia), 1972 (Box 6, Folder 53-54)
    - Christian Ethics and Revolution in Southern Africa (BUST), 1979 (Box 7, Folder 55)
    - Christianity and the Third World (PSR), 1973 (Box 7, Folder 56)
    - Christianity and Current World Issues (UTS), 1984, 1987,1990, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 57)
    - Christianity and Current World Issues: addendum (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - Christianity in Africa (YDS/BUST), 1977, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 58)
    - Church History (ETC, Rhodesia), 1971 (Box 7, Folder 59)
    - Church Revitalization (BUST/UTS), 1982,1984,1986 (Box 7, Folder 60)
    - Church Revitalization: addendum (Box 81, Folder 5)
    - Community Development: Mission, Economics and Politics (UTS), 1994,1999, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 61)
    - Community Development: addendum, Part I, 1999 (Box 83, Folder 1)
    - Community Development: addendum, Part II, 1999 (Box 83, Folder 2)
    - Current Issues in Missiology (UTS), 1992, 1994,1995,1996,1998,2000 (Box 8, Folder 62)
    - Current Issues in Missiology: addendum (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Current Issues in Missiology (UTS) case studies: "Should Kenyan Church Leaders Ask the President to Resign?"; "Singing the Lord's Song"; "I Was in Prison" (Box 82, Folder 2)
    - Current Issues in Missiology (UTS) case studies: "Should We Resist the Japanese?"; "Don't Come Over and Help Us!"; "Should I Baptize Them Now?"; "You Must Purify the House" (Box 82, Folder 3)
    - Current Issues in Missiology (UTS) case studies:"Initiation"; "Build Your Church Here"; "Tourism in Philippines"; "What Kind of God Would Let This Happen?" (Box 82, Folder 4)
    - Current Issues in Missiology (UTS) case studies: "Should I Accept?"; "The Call"; "Asia Resources"; "Come Holy Spirit(s)" (Box 82, Folder 5)
    - Dynamics of Church Growth (BUST/UTS), 1983,1987,1989,1993,1997 (Box 8, Folder 63)
    - Dynamics of Church Growth: addendum, 1993-1997 (Box 81, Folder 6)
    - Dynamics of Church Growth: addendum, 1993-1997 (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - Ecumenism and Mission (UTS), 1989,1991,1993,1995,1997,2000 (Box 8, Folder 64)
    - Ecumenism and Mission (UTS): addendum, 1997 (Box 81, Folder 2)
    - Emergence of hte Modern Church in Third World Perspective (BUST), 1980,1981,1982 (Box 8, Folder 65)
    - Internationalizing Christian Mission (BUST), 1980, 1981, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 66)
    - Lay Ministry (ETC, Rhodesia), 1972 (Box 8, Folder 67)
    - Living Religions (UTS), 1995, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 68)
    - Living Religions (UTS): addendum (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - Missiological Research and Method (UTS), 1993, 1994,1995,1997, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 69)
    - Missiological Research and Method (UTS): addendum (Box 81, Folder 3)
    - Mission and Evangelism in Contemporary Culture, 1983,1984,1986, 1988,1990,1992,1994,1996, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 70)
    - Mission and Evangelism in Contemporary Culture: addendum (Box 84, Folder 2-3)
    - Mission, Culture, and Social Change, 1993, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 71)
    - Mission, Culture, and Social Change: addendum (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - New Directions in Mission and Evangelism (UTS), 1995 (Box 9, Folder 72)
    - Patterns of Church Renewal and Growth (UTS), 2000 (Box 9, Folder 73)
    - Patterns of Church Renewal and Growth: addendum, 2000 (Box 85, Folder 3)
    - Religion and Society (ETC, Rhodesia), 1972 (Box 9, Folder 74)
    - Rethinking Mission and Evangelism (UTS), 1985, 1986, 1987, 1989, 1991, 1993, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 76)
    - Rethinking Mission and Evangelism: addendum (Box 84, Folder 4-5)
    - Rewriting Church History (UTS), 1999 (Box 9, Folder 77)
    - Rewriting Church History: addendum, 1999 (Box 85, Folder 4)
    - Social Issues in Ecumenical Perspective (BUST), 1978,1979,1980,1981 (Box 9, Folder 78)
    - Theological Issues in Mission and Evangelism (BUST/UTS), 1981,1984,1986,1988 (Box 9, Folder 79)
    - Theological Issues in Mission and Evangelism: addendum (Box 83, Folder 4)
    - Theology and Practice if Evangelism (UTS), 1983, 1984, 1985, 1986, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 80)
    - Theology of Liberation (PSR), 1973 (Box 10, Folder 81)
    - Theology of the Christian World Mission (UTS), 1992, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 82)
    - Theology of the Christian World Mission: addendum, 1994 (Box 85, Folder 1)
    - Third World Christianity (UTS), 1984, 1985, 1986, 1991, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 83)
    - Unity and Diversity in the Church (UTS), 1984, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 84)
    - Unity and Diversity in the Church: addendum (Box 85, Folder 5)
    - World Mission Seminars (UTS-OMSC), 1996,1997,1998 (Box 10, Folder 85)
    - Christianity in Africa Lecture Notes (Box 10, Folder 86)
    - Transparencies used in various courses (Box 85, Folder 2)
- Documentation Files by Subject, Series V
  - General Works
    - AC Bibliographies: Africa (Box 10, Folder 87)
  - Philosophy
    - BJ Ethics (Box 10, Folder 88)
  - BL.Religion
    - BL 1.5 Religions: Teaching; Syllabi (Box 10, Folder 89)
    - BL 100 Religions: General (Box 10, Folder 90)
    - BL 1100 Hinduism: General (Box 10, Folder 91)
    - BL 1300 Jainism (Box 10, Folder 92)
    - BL 1570 Zoroastrianism (Box 11, Folder 93)
    - BL 1800 Chinese Religions (Box 11, Folder 94)
    - BL 2200 Japanese Religions (Box 11, Folder 95)
    - BL 2400 African Religion: General (Box 11, Folder 96)
    - BM Judaism (Box 11, Folder 97)
    - BQ Buddhism (Box 11, Folder 98)
    - BP Islam (Box 11, Folder 99)
  - BR Church History
    - BR 100 Church History: General (Box 11, Folder 100)
    - BR 127 Christianity and Other Religions: General (Box 11, Folder 101)
    - BR 127D Interreligious Dialogue (Box 11, Folder 102)
    - BR 127T Theology of Religions (Box 12, Folder 103)
    - BR 128A Christianity and African Religion (Box 12, Folder 104)
    - BR 128A5 Christianity and Shona Religion (Zimbabwe) (Box 12, Folder 105)
    - BR 128B Christianity and Buddhism (Box 12, Folder 106)
    - BR 128C Christianity and Chinese Religions (Box 12, Folder 107)
    - BR 128H Christianity and Hinduism (Box 12, Folder 108)
    - BR 128I Christianity and Islam (Box 12, Folder 109)
    - BR128 I2 Christian-Muslim Relations: Newsletter of the Taskforce (NCCUSA) (Box 12, Folder 110)
    - BR 128J Christianity and Judaism (Box 12, Folder 111)
    - BR 128N Christianity and New Religions (Box 12, Folder 112)
    - BR 510 Church History: North America (USA) (Box 13, Folder 113)
    - BR 600 Church in Latin America (Box 13, Folder 114)
    - BR 640 Church in the Caribbean (Box 13, Folder 115)
    - BR 650 Church in Central America/Meso America (Box 13, Folder 116)
    - BR 735 Church in Europe (Box 13, Folder 117)
    - BR 950 Church in Great Britain (Box 14, Folder 118)
    - BR 1065 Church in Asia (including Christian Conference of Asia) (Box 14, Folder 119)
    - BR 1100 Church in East Asia: General (Hong Kong; Taiwan;Mongolia) (Box 14, Folder 120)
    - BR 1110 Church in China (Box 14, Folder 121-122)
    - BR 1130 Church in Japan (Box 14, Folder 123)
    - BR 1135 Church in Korea (Box 15, Folder 124)
    - BR 1150 Church in the Middle East (Box 15, Folder 125)
    - BR 1265 Church in Burma[Myanmar] (Box 15, Folder 126)
    - BR 1270 Church in India (Box 15, Folder 127)
    - BR 1300 Church in Southeast Asia: General (Box 15, Folder 128)
    - BR 1315 Church in Indonesia (Box 15, Folder 129)
    - BR 1325 Church in Malaysia (Box 15, Folder 130)
    - BR 1330 Church in the Philippines (Box 16, Folder 131)
    - BR 1335 Church in Singapore (Box 16, Folder 132)
    - BR 1340 Church in Thailand (Box 16, Folder 133)
    - BR 1345 Church in Vietnam, Laos, Cambodia (Box 16, Folder 134)
    - BR 1360 Church in Africa: General (Box 16, Folder 135)
    - BR 1363 Church in Central Africa (Box 16, Folder 137)
    - BR 1375 Church in Eastern Africa (Box 16, Folder 138)
    - BR 1400 Church in North Africa (Box 16, Folder 139)
    - BR 1415 Church in Southern Africa (Box 17, Folder 140)
    - BR 1416 Church in Angola (Box 17, Folder 141)
    - BR 1422 Church in Mozambique (Box 17, Folder 142)
    - BR 1430 Church in South Africa (Box 17, Folder 143)
    - BR 1435 Church in Zimbabwe [Southern Rhodesia; Rhodesia] (Box 17, Folder 144)
    - BR 1440 Church in West Africa (Box 17, Folder 145)
    - BR 1480 Church in Australia (Box 17, Folder 146)
    - BR 1482 Church in Melanesia (Box 17, Folder 147)
    - BR 1640 Evangelicalism (Box 17, Folder 148)
    - BR 1644 Pentecostalism; Charismatic Movement (Box 17, Folder 149)
  - BS Bible
    - BS 5 Bible: Study and Teaching (Box 18, Folder 150)
    - BS 10 Old Testament (Box 18, Folder 151)
    - BS 20 New Testament (Box 18, Folder 152)
  - BT Theology
    - BT 10 Theology: General (Box 18, Folder 153)
    - BT 40 Liberation Theologies (Box 18, Folder 154)
    - BT 42 Black Theologies (Box 18, Folder 155)
    - BT 43 Feminist Theologies (Box 18, Folder 156)
    - BT 100 God (Box 19, Folder 157)
    - BT 110 Holy Spirit (Box 19, Folder 158)
    - BT 200 Jesus Christ (Box 19, Folder 159)
    - BT 700 Humanity and Creation (Box 19, Folder 160)
    - BT 800 Sin And Salvation (Box 19, Folder 161)
    - BT 1100 Apologetics (Box 19, Folder 162)
  - BU-BX Church
    - BU 100 Nature of: General Works (Box 19, Folder 163)
    - BU 102 Structure; polity (Box 19, Folder 164)
    - BU 200 Church Renewal: General (Box 19, Folder 165)
    - BU 205 Renewal (Newsletter, Loveless, 1981-85) (Box 19, Folder 166)
    - BU 212 Joint Action for Mission (WCC) (Box 19, Folder 167)
    - Renewal History (Box 19, Folder 168)
    - BU 222 Renewal: Small Groups (Box 19, Folder 169)
    - BU 223 Methodist Class Meetings (Box 19, Folder 170)
    - BU 224.5 House Churches (Box 20, Folder 171)
    - BU 250 Centers of Renewal (Taizé) (Box 20, Folder 173)
    - BU 300 Church and Community: Social Welfare (Box 20, Folder 174)
    - BU 400 Church and Urban Community (Box 20, Folder 175)
    - BU 401 Justice Ministries (Box 20, Folder 176)
    - BU 402 Urban-Industrial Mission (Box 20, Folder 177)
    - BU 405 Urban-Industrial Mission: Africa (Box 20, Folder 178)
    - BU 500 Church and Rural Community (Box 21, Folder 179)
    - BU 620 Church and Women (Box 21, Folder 180)
    - BU 622 Church and Women: Africa (Box 21, Folder 181)
    - BU 700 Ministry: General (Box 21, Folder 182)
    - BU 720 Clergy (Box 21, Folder 183)
    - BU 750 Laity: General (Box 21, Folder 184)
    - BU 780 Diaconate (Box 22, Folder 185)
    - BU 790 Lay Training Centers (Box 22, Folder 186)
    - BU 900 Finance and Stewardship (Box 22, Folder 187)
    - BV 10 Worship: General (Box 22, Folder 188)
    - BV 15 Church Music (Box 22, Folder 189)
    - BV 110 Advent; Christmas (Box 22, Folder 190)
    - BV 120 Lent, Easter, Pentacost (Box 22, Folder 191)
    - BV 175 Liturgy; Worship Services (Box 22, Folder 192)
    - BV 200 Prayer (Box 22, Folder 193)
    - BV 210 Prayers (Box 23, Folder 194)
    - BV 300 Sacraments: General (Box 23, Folder 195)
    - BV 310 Baptism (Box 23, Folder 196)
    - BV 320 Eucharist; Holy Communion (Box 23, Folder 197)
    - BV 800 Catechetics (Box 23, Folder 198)
    - BV 1400 Christian Education: General (Box 23, Folder 199)
    - BV 1401 Education Newsletter (WCC) (Box 23, Folder 200)
    - BV 1600 Leadership Training (Box 23, Folder 201)
    - BV 1620 Group Work (Box 23, Folder 202)
    - BV 1700 Christian Education: Children (Box 23, Folder 203)
    - BV 1800 Christian Education: Youth (Box 23, Folder 204)
    - BV 1900 Christian Education: Adults (Box 23, Folder 205)
    - BV 1910 Christian Home and Family Life (Box 24, Folder 206)
    - BV 1950 Christian Home and Family Life: Africa (Box 24, Folder 207)
    - BV 4000 Pastoral Theology: Counseling (Box 24, Folder 208)
    - BV 4050 Healing Ministries (Box 24, Folder 209)
    - BV 4100 Theological Education: General (Box 24, Folder 210)
    - BV 4105 Theological Education: USA (Box 24, Folder 211)
    - BV 4110 Theological Education: USA: Globalization Programs (Box 24, Folder 212)
    - BV 4110 Globalization in T.E. Seminary Programs in USA (Box 25, Folder 213)
    - BV 4120 Theological Education: USA: Field Education/Internships (Box 25, Folder 214)
    - BV 4140 Theological Education: Case Studies in Teaching (Box 25, Folder 215)
    - BV 4160 Theological Education: Third World (Box 25, Folder 216)
    - BV 4200 Homiletics (Preaching) (Box 25, Folder 217)
    - BV 4300 Christian Communication (Box 25, Folder 218)
    - BV 4310 Audio-Visual (Box 25, Folder 219)
    - BV 4350 Media Ministries (Electronic Church) (Box 25, Folder 221)
    - BV 4400 Special Ministries (Box 25, Folder 222)
    - BV 4500 Spirituality (Box 26, Folder 223)
    - BV 5000 Christian Life and Lifestyle (Box 26, Folder 224)
    - BX 1 Ecumenics: General (Box 26, Folder 225)
    - BX 1.0 Ecumenics: Syllabi (Box 26, Folder 226)